EVAN DANA

Sr. Software Engineer Boston, MA ☑ evan.writes.code@gmail.com

n @evandana

in evandana

evandana.com

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER WITH A FOCUS ON ARCHITECTING SUCCESSFUL WEB AND MOBILE EXPERIENCES. Specializing in front-end technologies, I deliver customer value through leadership and collaborative roles: as an individual contributor, technical lead, and counsel for stakeholders. I enjoy providing technical mentorship and stay current with tools and patterns. I approach challenges with engaging energy and passion.

Work History

Pear Therapeutics

Sr. Software Engineer

Increased efficiency of prescription digital therapeutic (PDT) mobile app development through ownership of shared UI libraries. Led planning, coordination, and development of major features and components requiring multiple engineers across teams. Improved engineering community through large and small initiatives. Strong collaborator, using documentation and diagramming to maintain aligned understanding and expectations. Delivered complex stories independently, focusing on value-based delivery.

General Electric | GE Digital

Sr. Software Engineer

For an IIOT monitoring dashboard app that minimized machine down time, delivered complex features in a timely manner, independently and through collaboration, with utmost attention to quality. Exemplified best practices from coding patterns to agile methodologies. Translated requirements into manageable stories with clear and complete acceptance criteria, raising discussions early if needed. Ensured quality by writing unit and system tests for use in CI/CD workflow. Consistently created useful graphical and text-based documentation.

Mentored software engineers and presented on modern UI frameworks and patterns through the use of interactive programming session.

Publicis.Sapient | Sapient Consulting

Sr. Interactive Developer, L2

2019 - Current | Boston, MA

React Native, React-Native-Testing-Library, TypeScript, Bitrise.io, Software as a Medical Device, PDT

- Drove Complex Cross-Team Initiatives To Success (Platform Engineer)
 Organized, planned, and implemented mobile-centric facet of cross-functionally complex project, spanning several teams. For migration to new auth service, consolidated requirements and solution options into a detailed RFC and living documentation for continued collaboration. Identified critical paths and opportunities for parallelization across teams, proactively collaborating to find solutions.
- Increased PDT Development Efficiency through Shared UI Libraries (Mobile Platform Engineer)
 Tech lead and primary contributor to the set of shared libraries used by the other Pear apps.
 Functionality includes utility classes, service API abstraction layer, and a UI flow for the Login experience. Led an app-team collaboration requiring new core components; crafted implementation strategy and tackled the most complex stories with composable components.
- Delivered PDT for Study Use (Tech Lead)
 Responsible for coordinating code delivery, quality, and providing technical estimates for full-stack
 React Native app with 3 other engineers. Delivered properly functioning app to app stores on time for study participants.
- Improved the Employee Experience (Chair of Employee Engagement Council)
 Worked cross-functionally, with executive team (C-suite), leadership team (VPs), and all employees, to ensure underserved voices are heard. Proposed solution recommendations to leadership based on aligned goals. Allocated EEC funds to create opportunities for shared experiences and relief for common stressors in this unusual time.
- Fostered Engineering Community (Engineering Advocate)
 3rd year running monthly Tech Talks, providing opportunities for knowledge sharing and practicing technical speaking. Co-organized and led the first two annual engineering-wide hackathons;
 Hackathon produced a self-service site (still in use) and PoC investigations that facilitated future permanent work; the cross-functional teamwork has lasting effects.

2016 - 2019 | Boston, MA

ES6, Polymer, WebSockets, NodeJS, CI/CD, Agile, Domain Modeling, Docker, AngularJS, ProUI, Bash scripting, Markdown documentation

- Community thought leader and advocate
 SME across teams for UI frameworks and patterns
- Feature lead
 Led UI development of feature on open source shared component library: px-data-table (https://github.com/predixdesignsystem/px-data-table/pull/126)
- Team contributor

 Focusing on group success, I drove inclusive discussions; improved maintainability with useful documentation and code reviews
- Independent feature delivery
 Implemented complex features and refactorings; added in-depth E2E tests and UI/UX designs.

2013 - 2016 | Boston, MA

ES6, D3.js, AngularJS, Aurelia, Agile, JSPM, NodeJS, Continuous Integration, Hexagonal Architecture (server-side), Domain-Driven Development, Domain Modeling, JIRA UI lead and front-end developer with aptitude for team dynamics, group coordination, and process efficiencies.

Awarded recognition for Client-Focused Delivery after client feedback on project when leading UI development with recently self-taught technology.

Years of experience in UI lead role, conducting engaging presentations, and as technical liaison for client and internal domain teams. Enforced code quality using best practices such as John DePapa's style guide and BEM on Agile projects. Self-motivated and driven: exemplified by creation of D3.js library and initiation of effective team-building program. Advocated for code stability through unit, integration, functional, or automated visual-diff testing.

- Autonomous and motivated
 Created reusable d3.js charting library between projects
- Quickly learned and utilized new technology From Backbone to AngularJS and Aurelia

Putnam Investments

Javascript UI Developer

Innerscope Research Inc.

Interactive Developer, L2

2012 – 2013 | Boston, MA JavaScript (jQuery, Highcharts), CSS, HTML, Backbone.js, Modernizr, SVN

2009 - 2012 | Boston, MA

HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Photoshop, Illustrator

Code Highlights

Non-profit Intake App: AHOPE / Boston Public Health Commission

Leading a team to create an patient intake app for a local nonprofit harm reduction center called AHOPE

(https://www.bphc.org/whatwedo/Recovery-Services/servicesfor-active-users/Pages/Services-for-Active-Users-AHOPE.aspx) who is managed by BPHC

(https://www.bphc.org/Pages/default.aspx) . Ascertaining and documenting requirements from business stakeholders. Bringing together experts (domain, UX, legal, medical, technical) and driving consensus. Managing a small group of software engineers who are mostly donating time for this project: ensuring coordinated efforts, timely delivery, and continued engagement. Utilizing GitHub projects to achieve agile development, stay focused on MVP and keep stakeholders informed.

2018 - Present

NestJS, TypeORM, Azure Cloud products, ReactJS 15.1.x, Redux, PostgresQL, Google Cloud, Parse, WebSockets, Material-UI, Google OAuth, ES6, Babel, Open source, GitHub Projects

- Form submission, profile search, profile update, and aggregation reports
- Transitioned from Firebase to Google Cloud Services to Microsoft Azure based on updated IAM requirements.
- Backend completely rebuilt with NestJS, previously Google Firebase then Parse (with MongoDB)
- Secure sign-in using Microsoft Azure

PMC Auction App

2016 - 2018

ReactJS 15.1.x, Redux, WebSockets, Firebase.io, Material-UI, Google OAuth, ES6, Babel, Domain Modeling, Trello, ESLint, Webback

Education History

React Advanced Composition Patterns Workshop

2021 | Online Workshop by React

React Hooks Workshop

2019 | Online Workshop by React Training Coursera.org

2012 – 2013 | Stanford University Online Harvard Extension School

Mobile Operating Systems and Applications

2013 - 2013 | Cambridge, MA

Rochester Institute of Technology

Bachelor, Industrial Design

2001 – 2005 | Rochester, NY

Activities

2-day JS Mobile Conference Attendee

JS Mobile Conf

2018 & 2019 | Boston, MA

Fitness Group Co-leader

November Project, Boston

2014 - 2015 | Boston, MA

D3.js Instructor

General Assembly

2015 | Boston, MA

Github

• AHOPE (HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/EVANDANA/KEEP-AHOPE) 2018 - PRESENT Patient intake app for AHOPE / BPHC

• FLUTTER NAV POC (HTTPS://EVANDANA.COM/FLUTTER-POC/README.HTML) 2021 - PRESENT Initial Flutter exploration into a nested navigation flow with independent modules

• AUCTION APP (HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/EVANDANA/PMC-AUCTION) 2018 Charitable-focused auction app including bucketed raffles

STREAM CORRELATION (HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/EVANDANA/STREAM-CORRELATION) 2018
Generate random data streams and show which ones are correlated

• REPO FOR THIS SITE (HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/EVANDANA/EVANDANA.GITHUB.IO) 2018

Jekyll template with UX modifications